

PERSONAL INFO

Address

Cala Millor, Spain

Contact

Portfolio: rrmarto.github.io
LinkedIn: rrmarto

Abilities

- Algorithm design.
- Analysis and design of solutions.
- High level of abstraction.
- Systems requirements engineering.
- Unitary and functional testing.
- Teamwork.
- Adaptability to changing environments.

Technologies

Programming Languages:

Java, Dart, Swift, C#.

Web: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, PHP.

Frameworks:

Flutter, Spring MVC, Spring Boot, Bootstrap, JQuery.

WS: SOAP, REST, GraphQL, Websockets.

DB: PostgreSQL, MySql, Oracle, MongoDB.

CVS: Git, SVN, RTC, TFS.

IDE: Eclipse, Netbeans, IntelliJ IDEA, Visual Studio Code, Android Studio, XCode.

Testing: JUnit, Mockito.

Methodologies: Scrum, XP, RUP.

Design: Adobe XD, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe Photoshop, Rive.

Cloud: AWS, Firebase, Github.

Languages

Spanish: Native.

English:

Intermediate/Advanced proficiency .

Roberto Marto Ramirez

SENIOR MOBILE DEVELOPER

Computer Sciences Engineer (Havana, UCI, 2013), experienced in mobile development with a demonstrated history of working in the information technology and services industry. Strong engineering skills with knowledge in Java, Android, iOS, Flutter, Agile Methodologies, Databases and Cloud Services.

EXPERIENCE

Lead Mobile Developer

CODELIGHT Dic, 2021–Jul, 2022

- Develop Android and iOS applications using Flutter, delivering stable, testable, and maintainable software applications.
- Run a variety of software testing procedures including writing unit and UI tests to identify
 malfunctions and bugs, before designing and implementing innovative solutions to solve
 them.
- Research, recommend and implement new technologies to increase app development productivity.
- Create project estimations, project plans and risk assessments for each application in development.

Senior Mobile Developer

YOGO MS CORP

Oct, 2019-Dic, 2021

- Support with the entire application lifecycle including concept, design, testing, release, and support.
- Analysis of user requirements and translation of customer needs into application design.
- Clean, modular, and robust code using state management.
 - Created and published apps for Android and ios using flutter.

Mobile Developer

FREELANCE

Sept, 2016-Oct, 2019

Apr, 2014-Jul, 2016

Sept, 2013-Mar, 2014

- Supported the entire application project lifecycle from concept, design, testing, release, and post-launch support.
- Liaised with clients to understand their requirements, making appropriate suggestions if required.
- Wrote high quality source code to program complete applications while working to tight deadlines.
- Designed application interfaces to improve the overall user experience.

Full Stack Developer

GDAI

- Implementation of SOAP and REST web services.
- Implementation of web interfaces.
- Implementation of Android apps using Java.
- Modeling of database structures in Oracle and PostgresQL.

Computer Science Specialist

University of Informatic Science

- Design and implementation of web interfaces.
- Design and implementation of unit tests using JUnit.
- Implementation of Android apps using Java.
- Advanced Administration of GNU / Linux Systems.

Training

Postgraduate course: Advanced Mobile Development, 2015, Havana Cuba.

Postgraduate course: Advanced management in GNU/Linux, 2014, Havana, Cuba.

Postgraduate course: Android Development,2013, Havana,

EDUCATION

Computer Science Engineer

University of Informatic Science

Mar, 2008-Jul, 2013

CORE SKILLS

